{
    "title": "Phospholipids & Cyclooxygenase",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "1. Which of the following is a potent sleep-promoting substance?",
        "options": ["PG12", "PGF2", "PGE2", "PGD2"],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "2. The function of PGE is:",
        "options": [
          "maintain pain & fever",
          "vasoconstriction",
          "promote sleep",
          "non of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "3. Lipoxygenase is the enzyme responsible for synthesis of:",
        "options": ["PG", "prostacyclin", "thromboxane", "leukotrienes"],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "4. Prostanoids include:",
        "options": ["PG", "prostacyclin", "thromboxane", "all of the above"],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "5. The type of PG that promote sleep is:",
        "options": ["PGE", "PGF", "PGF", "PGD"],
        "correct": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "6. Aspirin is non selective inhibitor of:",
        "options": [
          "cyclooxygenase",
          "lipoxygenase",
          "thromboxane synthase",
          "non"
        ],
        "correct": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "7. One of the following can act as anti-allergic and anti-inflammatory:",
        "options": ["aspirin", "ketoprofen", "corticosteroids", "all of the above"],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "8. The best anti-inflammatory drug with less side effects is:",
        "options": [
          "anti-cox 1",
          "anti-cox 2",
          "non selective anti-cox",
          "leukotriene receptors blocker"
        ],
        "correct": 1
      },
          {
        "question": "9. All of the following mediators can cause vasodilatation except:",
        "options": ["histamine", "PG", "NO", "reactive oxygen species"],
        "correct": 3
      },
          {
        "question": "10. All of the following are characters of COX except......",
        "options": ["They act on A.A", "Has two subtypes", "Non-suicidal Enzyme", "Is a bis-dioxygenase"],
        "correct": 2
      }
    ]
  }
